<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Publications on Elena Pagnin</title>
    <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Publications on Elena Pagnin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://epagnin.github.io/papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Count Me In! Extendability for Threshold Ring Signatures</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2022-extrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2022-extrs/</guid>
      <description>Ring signatures enable a signer to sign a message on behalf of a group anonymously, without revealing her identity. Similarly, threshold ring signatures allow several signers to sign the same message on behalf of a group; while the combined signature reveals that some threshold t of the group members signed the message, it does not leak anything else about the signers’ identities. Anonymity is a central feature in threshold ring signature applications, such as whistleblowing, e-voting and privacy-preserving cryptocurrencies: it is often crucial for signers to remain anonymous even from their fellow signers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progressive And Effcient Verification For Digital Signatures</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2022-flabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2022-flabs/</guid>
      <description>Digital signatures are widely deployed to authenticate the source of incoming information, or to certify data integrity. Common signature verification procedures return a decision (accept/reject) only at the very end of the execution. If interrupted prematurely, however, the verification process cannot infer any meaningful information about the validity of the given signature. We notice that this limitation is due to the algorithm design solely, and it is not inherent to signature verification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LOVE a Pairing</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2021-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2021-love/</guid>
      <description>The problem of securely outsourcing the computation of a bilinear pairing has been widely investigated in the literature. Designing an eﬀicient protocol with the desired functionality has, however, been an open challenge for a long time. Recently, Di Crescenzo et al. (CARDIS’20) proposed the first suite of protocols for securely and eﬀiciently delegating pairings with online inputs under the presence of a malicious server. We progress along this path with the aim of LOVE (Lowering the cost of Outsourcing and Verifying Eﬀiciently) a pairing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yggdrasil: Privacy-aware Dual Deduplication in Multi Client Settings</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2021-yggrdasil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2021-yggrdasil/</guid>
      <description>This paper proposes Yggdrasil, a protocol for privacy-aware dual data deduplication in multi client settings. Yggdrasil is designed to reduce the cloud storage space while safeguarding the privacy of the client’s outsourced data. Yggdrasil combines three innovative tools to achieve this goal. First, generalized deduplication, an emerging technique to reduce data footprint. Second, non-deterministic transformations that are described compactly and improve the degree of data compression in the Cloud (across users).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where are you Bob? Privacy-Preserving Proximity Testing with a Napping Party</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2020-olic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2020-olic/</guid>
      <description>Location based services (LBS) extensively utilize proximity testing to help people discover nearby friends, devices, and services. Current practices rely on full trust to the service providers: users share their locations with the providers who perform proximity testing on behalf of the users. Unfortunately, location data has been often breached by LBS providers, raising privacy concerns over the current practices. To address these concerns previous research has suggested cryptographic protocols for privacy-preserving location proximity testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Generalized Deduplication via Multi-Key Revealing Encryption</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2020-mkre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2020-mkre/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Storage Providers (CSPs) offer solutions to relieve users from locally storing vast amounts of data, including personal and sensitive ones. While users may desire to retain some privacy on the data they outsource, CSPs are interested in reducing the total storage space by employing compression techniques such as deduplication. We propose a new cryptographic primitive that simultaneously realizes both requirements: Multi-Key Revealing Encryption (MKRE). The goal of MKRE is to disclose the result of a predefined function over multiple ciphertexts, even if the ciphertexts were generated using different keys, while revealing nothing else about the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOPPool: time-aware optimized privacy-preserving ridesharing</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2019-toppool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2019-toppool/</guid>
      <description>Ridesharing is revolutionizing the transportation industry in many countries. Yet, the state of the art is based on heavily centralized services and platforms, where the service providers have full possession of the users’ location data. Recently, researchers have started addressing the challenge of enabling privacy-preserving ridesharing. The initial proposals, however, have shortcomings, as some rely on a central party, some incur high performance penalties, and most do not consider time preferences for ridesharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The simplest multi-key linearly homomorphic signature scheme</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2019-simplest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2019-simplest/</guid>
      <description>We consider the problem of outsourcing computation on data authenticated by different users. Our aim is to describe and implement the simplest possible solution to provide data integrity in cloud-based scenarios. Concretely, our multi-key linearly homomorphic signature scheme (mklhs) allows users to upload signed data on a server, and at any later point in time any third party can query the server to compute a linear combination of data authenticated by different users and check the correctness of the returned result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAID: Reshaping Signal into an Identity-Based Asynchronous Messaging Protocol with Authenticated Ratcheting</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2019-said/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2019-said/</guid>
      <description>As messaging applications are becoming increasingly popular, it is of utmost importance to analyze their security and mitigate existing weaknesses. This paper focuses on one of the most acclaimed messaging applications: Signal. Signal is a protocol that provides end-to-end channel security, forward secrecy, and post-compromise security. These features are achieved thanks to a key-ratcheting mechanism that updates the key material at every message. Due to its high security impact, Signal’s key-ratcheting has recently been formalized, along with an analysis of its security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-key homomorphic authenticators</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2019-04-29-multi-key-ha-j/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2019-04-29-multi-key-ha-j/</guid>
      <description>Homomorphic authenticators (HAs) enable a client to authenticate a large collection of data elements m_1,&amp;hellip;,m_t and outsource them, along with the corresponding authenticators, to an untrusted server. At any later point, the server can generate a short authenticator sigma_(f,y) vouching for the correctness of the output y of a function f computed on the outsourced data, i.e., y = f(m_1,&amp;hellip;,m_t). Recently researchers have focused on HAs as a solution, with minimal communication and interaction, to the problem of delegating computation on outsourced data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIKE: Walking the Privacy Trail</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2018-07-07-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2018-07-07-hike/</guid>
      <description>We consider the problem of privacy-preserving processing of outsourced data in the context of user-customised services. Clients store their data on a server. In order to provide user-dependent services, service providers may ask the server to compute functions on the users’ data. We propose a new solution to this problem that guarantees data privacy (i.e., an honest-but-curious server cannot access plaintexts), as well as that service providers can correctly decrypt only –functions on– the data the user gave them access to (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matrioska: A Compiler for Multi-Key Homomorphic Signatures</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2018-matrioska/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2018-matrioska/</guid>
      <description>Multi-Key Homomorphic Signatures (MK-HS) enable clients in a system to sign and upload messages to an untrusted server. At any later point in time, the server can perform a computation C on data provided by t different clients, and return the output y and a short signature vouching for the correctness of y as the output of the function C on the signed data. Interestingly, MK-HS enable verifiers to check the validity of the signature using solely the public keys of the signers whose messages were used in the computation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HB&#43;DB: Distance bounding meets human based authentication</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2018-hbdbmeets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2018-hbdbmeets/</guid>
      <description>Authentication for resource-constrained devices is seen as one of the major challenges in current wireless communication networks. The HB+ protocol by Juels and Weis provides device authentication based on the learning parity with noise (LPN) problem and is appropriate for resource-constrained devices, but it has been shown to be vulnerable to a simple man-in-the-middle attack. Subsequent work has focused on modifying the cryptographic properties of the original protocol to mitigate this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anonymous Single-Round Server-Aided Verification</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2017-09-20-sav/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2017-09-20-sav/</guid>
      <description>Server-Aided Verification (SAV) is a method that can be em- ployed to speed up the process of verifying signatures by letting the verifier outsource part of its computation load to a third party. Achieving fast and reliable verification under the presence of an untrusted server is an attractive goal in cloud computing and internet of things scenarios. In this paper, we describe a simple framework for SAV where the interaction between a verifier and an untrusted server happens via a single-round protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Yasuda et al.’s Biometric Authentication Protocol: Are you Private Enough?</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2017-private-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2017-private-enough/</guid>
      <description>Biometric Authentication Protocols (BAPs) have increasingly been employed to guarantee reliable access control to places and services. However, it is well-known that biometric traits contain sensitive information of individuals and if compromised could lead to serious security and privacy breaches. Yasuda et al. [23] proposed a distributed privacy-preserving BAP which Abidin et al. [1] have shown to be vulnerable to biometric template recovery attacks under the presence of a malicious computational server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-hop Distance-Bounding Protocols: Keep your Friends Close</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2017-twohopdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2017-twohopdb/</guid>
      <description>Distance-bounding (DB) protocols are cross-layer authentication protocols that are based on the round-trip-time of challenge-response exchanges and can be employed to guarantee physical proximity and combat relay attacks. However, traditional DB protocols rely on the assumption that the prover is in the communication range of the verifier, which might not be the case in multiple access control scenarios in ubiquitous computing environments or when we need to verify the proximity of our two-hop neighbour in an ad-hoc network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-preserving biometric authentication: challenges and directions</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2017-10-19-biomagazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2017-10-19-biomagazine/</guid>
      <description>An emerging direction for authenticating people is the adoption of biometric authentication systems. Biometric credentials are becoming increasingly popular as a means of authenticating people due to the wide range of advantages that they provide with respect to classical authentication methods (e.g., password-based authentication). The most characteristic feature of this authentication method is the naturally strong bond between a user and her biometric credentials. This very same advantageous property, however, raises serious security and privacy concerns in case the biometric trait gets compromised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-key homomorphic authenticators</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2016-mkha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2016-mkha/</guid>
      <description>Homomorphic authenticators (HAs) enable a client to authenticate a large collection of data elements m_1,&amp;hellip;,m_t and outsource them, along with the corresponding authenticators, to an untrusted server. At any later point, the server can generate a short authenticator sigma_(f,y) vouching for the correctness of the output y of a function f computed on the outsourced data, i.e., y = f(m_1,&amp;hellip;,m_t). Recently researchers have focused on HAs as a solution, with minimal communication and interaction, to the problem of delegating computation on outsourced data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using distance-bounding protocols to securely verify the proximity of two-hop neighbours</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2015-07-01-using-db/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2015-07-01-using-db/</guid>
      <description>Distance-bounding protocols allow devices to cryptographically verify the physical proximity of two parties and is a prominent secure neighbour detection method. We describe how existing distance-bounding protocols could be modified to verify the proximity of both next-hop and two-hop neighbours. This approach allows a node to verify that another node is a physical next-hop neighbour, and also detects legitimate neighbours who make dishonest claims as to who their neighbours are. This approach could prevent dishonest neighbours from hoarding traffic as the result of advertising false two-hop routes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HB&#43;DB, Mitigating Man-in-the-Middle Attacks Against HB&#43; with Distance Bounding</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2015-06-25-short-hbdb-mitigating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2015-06-25-short-hbdb-mitigating/</guid>
      <description>Authentication for resource-constrained devices is seen as one of the major challenges in current wireless communication networks.
The HB+ protocol performs device authentication based on the learning parity with noise (LPN) problem and simple computational steps, that renders it suitable for resource-constrained devices such as radio frequency identification (RFID) tags. However, it has been shown that the HB+ protocol as well as many of its variants are vulnerable to a simple man-in-the-middle attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Leakage of Information in Biometric Authentication.</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2014-on-the-leakage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 15:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/papers/2014-on-the-leakage/</guid>
      <description>In biometric authentication protocols, a user is authenticated or granted access to a service if her fresh biometric trait matches the reference biometric template stored on the service provider. This matching process is usually based on a suitable distance which measures the similarities between the two biometric templates. In this paper, we prove that, when the matching process is performed using a specific family of distances (which includes distances such as the Hamming and the Euclidean distance), then information about the reference template is leaked.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
