<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscellanea on Elena Pagnin</title>
    <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscellanea on Elena Pagnin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://epagnin.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Academic Spam</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2023-04-20-aspam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2023-04-20-aspam/</guid>
      <description>What is Academic Spam? Yes, academia is not immune to spam! and here I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about &amp;rsquo;the usual&amp;rsquo; kind of spam, but the one that is targeted to academic. This often comes with emails addressed to Dear colleague, Respected Sir, or in the more sophisticated cases they actually parse your name (usually from bibliographic references, so that it spells surname first or with odd shortening), and offers invitation to submit your work to (fictional) conferences or (scamy and irrelevant) journals with low-quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does the peer-review system work?</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-09-01-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-09-01-review/</guid>
      <description>Basics principles of peer-reviewing You submit your work. A few people read it, usually the magic number of reviewers is 3, and they are supposed to be experts in the topic of your paper. These people say what they think about your paper. Your paper gets accepted or rejecting according to the reviewers&amp;rsquo; opinions and possibly a sanity check by the general chair of the conference.
What do reviewers look for in a paper?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to determine quality of papers</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-07-01-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-07-01-quality/</guid>
      <description>How to determine quality of papers There are different metrics to measure &amp;lsquo;how good&amp;rsquo; a paper is. None is perfect or completely accurate. The best way to judge is personal, and you will develop your own preferences and &amp;lsquo;qualities indicators&amp;rsquo; over time.
The San Francisco Declaration on Research Assessment (DORA) opens with this statement:
There is a pressing need to improve the ways in which the output of scientific research is evaluated by funding agencies, academic institutions, and other parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Questions</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-06-08-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-06-08-interview/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re preparing for an interview (either as interviewee or interviewer), this is a good link to check out! It&amp;rsquo;s essentially a bot that returns common hiring questions for faculty appointments within computer science. Here you get a pdf with a good pool of questions for practicing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this website</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2020-04-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2020-04-website/</guid>
      <description>How did I build this website? For academics, I think having a personal website is quite important as it allows you to quickly advertise news, collect and organize your work, and, most importantly, it is a great way for everyone around the world to know you exist and what you&amp;rsquo;re up to.
For several years I have used jekyll, but it started to get messy with the latest OS updates and gem versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2020-04-27-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2020-04-27-latex/</guid>
      <description>Handy links for LaTeX Detexify automatic recognition of handwritten symbols latexpand to automatically combine all latex files into a single file. (If full latex is installed, you just need to type this command line: latexpand -empty-comments -o main_one_file.tex main.tex the long file output will appear in the Terminal) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIT &amp;co</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2020-04-27-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2020-04-27-git/</guid>
      <description>Handy links for GIT Git is an amazing tool for collaborative projects. In a nutshell, it enables version controlling of whatever collection of digital data you log in it. When writing a paper with other people, git makes it easy to trace changes, to ensure everyone can reach the most recent version of the text / code / experiments, and, if needed, to revert in time to restore previous versions. As a PhD student, if you want to do research with me, knowing how to navigate git is a prerequisite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Readings (Research Articles)</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-05-12-readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-05-12-readings/</guid>
      <description>The body of literature around cryptographic techniques and provable security is enormous. To help newcomers approach the community I am collecting a list of nice papers that hopefully provide an easy introduction to the main branches of cryptography and the way formal reasoning works.
New Directions in Cryptoraphy by Diffie and Hellman, in IEEE Transactions on information theory, 1978. This is THE Diffie Hellman paper, the stepping stone into public-key and computational cryptography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice Books</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-09-16-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-09-16-books/</guid>
      <description>📙 Captivate: The Science of Succeeding with People by Vanessa Van Edwards
📙 Develop Your Presentation Skills: How to Inspire and Inform with Clarity and Confidence by Theo Theobald
📙 From Research to Manuscript A Guide to Scientific Writing by Michael Jay Katz</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice Books</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2023-02-02-pods/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2023-02-02-pods/</guid>
      <description>List of nice podcast about Cryptography and Real world Security 🎧 Darknet Diaries, fascinating interviews and stories about several famous event and people (enjoyable even if you are not tech-savvy).
🎧 Cryptography FM, interviews and discussions about recent progresses in cryptography. Particularly relevant for PhD students and people that study and work with cryptography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for presentations</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-04-08-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-04-08-presentations/</guid>
      <description>Looking for Copyright-free material for slides? Here&amp;rsquo;s some useful links to images databases: pikwizard, freepik, unsplash, pxfuel.
Here&amp;rsquo;s my go-to place for free clipart, and icons
My favorite place
Tools to help you visualize the size of things When numbers are so big that it&amp;rsquo;s too hard to get an understanding of their magnitude some resources might come handy: the mesure of things to compare the quantity to other more-or-less well-known things; or numbermatics to get facts on the number itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things you should know</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2020-04-27-phd-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2020-04-27-phd-qa/</guid>
      <description>This post contains some common Q&amp;amp;A for PhD students:
Q: Where can I look for papers to read and study? A: In the beginning of your PhD, start by looking at the list of accepted papers at top- and mid-level conferences. You can do this by googling the conference name, a year and search for a link of &amp;lsquo;accepted papers&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;program&amp;rsquo;. [Names of conferences: CRYPTO, EUROCRYPT, ASIACRYPT, PKC, Theory of Cryptography Conference] Some conferences also provide video recordings of the presentations (which is a time-efficient way to get what the paper is about).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tipps for Good Teaching Practice</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2021-10-11-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2021-10-11-teaching/</guid>
      <description>Tipps for Good Teaching Practice As part of your PhD education at LTH, you will take some pedagogical courses regarding teaching, learning and how to evaluate students&amp;rsquo; learning. But when it comes to it, how do you structure a lecture? Here and here you can find a list of clear and valuable pointers to keep in mind when preparing yourself to this task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Links</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-04-08-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-04-08-links/</guid>
      <description>Efficiently decide on a meeting date and time When2meet lets people fill in their availability in a calendar form, instead of flooding people with numerous options. What was the Latex command for that symbol? Detexify automatic recognition of handwritten symbols Good English Ngram Viewer is a useful tool that checks how frequent a certain word, name or expression (sequence of few words) is common in the English literature. It is a simple way to check correctness of words bending and preposition for non-native speakers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Cryptography?</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-01-20-crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2022-01-20-crypto/</guid>
      <description>What is Cryptography? Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick video explaining the magic you can do with cryptography.
If you are working with me, chances are that we stumble upon some cryptographic primitive, security proof, or privacy challenge. In order to have fruitful discussion, it is very important that you get an understanding of the general framework used in cryptography, how primitives are formalized and how to reason about security model, attackers and proofs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wondering what other researchers think?</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2021-07-24-mentoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2021-07-24-mentoring/</guid>
      <description>Mentoring videos by the IACR community The International Association for Cryptologic Research (IACR) launched an initiative to provide advice for researchers in early stages (students and junior faculty) and women researchers in the area of cryptography. In this series of videos you can listen to the answers a pool of community members gives to a wide range of questions, most of which you will stumble upon at a certain point in your academic career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with me and at Chalmers</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2023-02-10-workingwithme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2023-02-10-workingwithme/</guid>
      <description>Meet me, and my research projects 🎬 I&amp;rsquo;m a Cryptographer, I&amp;rsquo;m paid to be paranoid
🎬 Future-Oriented Research: “Enhancing Data Authentication”
How does it feel to be a PhD student at Chalmers? 🎬 Interview to a first year PhD student</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the next deadline???</title>
      <link>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2021-01-01-deadlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://epagnin.github.io/posts/2021-01-01-deadlines/</guid>
      <description>Check out my selection of deadlines for conference on stuff I like to do research on (sporadically updated).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
